Preliminary Inventory of the William Offutt Doub Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
William Offutt Doub papers
1970-1974
2012C12
Doub, William Offutt, 1931-
165 manuscript boxes (68.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, speeches and writings, memoranda, minutes, reports, studies, and printed matter, relating to nuclear energy in the United States, including licensing of nuclear power plants and nuclear safety issues.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Collection stored off site; a minimum of two days notice is required for use. Boxes may be requested through Stanford's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2011.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Doub was a member of the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) from 1971 to 1974. During his tenure at the AEC, the commission reorganized and restructured the agency's regulatory program. He directed an agency report, "Federal Energy Regulation: An Organizational Study," that recommended a number of practical changes designed to increase the agency's ability to respond more quickly to changes in technology and economic conditions.
Doub was a Republican Party candidate for statewide office in his native Maryland. He held a number of appointed positions there (including chairman of the Maryland Public Service Commission) before assuming his role at the AEC.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, speeches and writings, memoranda, minutes, reports, studies, and printed matter, relating to nuclear energy in the United States, including licensing of nuclear power plants and nuclear safety issues.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
U.S. Atomic Energy Commission.; Nuclear energy--United States.
Collection Contents
- Audio tapes (Box 1)
- Congressional hearing materials (Box 2-4)
- AEC Year 2000 study (Box 5-6)
- Martin J. Domagala notes (Box 7-8)
- Trip files, 1973-1974 (Box 9-10)
- AEC minutes and policy sessions, 1971-1974 (Box 11-12)
- Trip files, 1973 (Box 13-15)
- Calendars, travel vouchers, telephone logs, employment applications (Box 16-18)
- Subject files (Box 19-24)
- Trip files, 1972 (Box 25-27)
- Subject files (Box 28-29)
- Miscellany (Box 30)
- Speeches, 1971-1974 (Box 31)
- Trip files, 1972 (Box 32-34)
- Chronological files, 1973-1974 (Box 35-37)
- Speeches by others (Box 38-40)
- Trip files, 1973-1974 (Box 41-43)
- Subject files (Box 44-45)
- Printed Congressional hearing reports (Box 46-49)
- Books and technical reports (Box 50-52)
- Subject files (Box 53-54)
- Congressional appropriation and authorization hearing materials (Box 55-57)
- Subject files (Box 58-62)
- Trip files, 1973 (Box 63-65)
- Subject files (Box 66-67)
- Trip files, 1971-1972 (Box 68-70)
- AEC regulations and handbooks (Box 71-72)
- Technical reports (Box 73-75)
- Subject files (Box 76-83)
- Calvert Cliffs Nuclear Power Plant files (Box 84-86)
- Subject files (Box 87-89)
- Trip files, 1972-1973 (Box 90-92)
- AEC handbooks (Box 93-94)
- Liquid Metal Fast Breeder Reactor plans (Box 95-96)
- Liquid Metal Fast Breeder Reactor environmental impact statement (Box 97-98)
- Subject files (Box 99-104)
- Speeches, 1971-1974 (Box 105-106)
- Subject files (Box 107-108)
- Personal files (Box 109-110)
- Trip files, 1972 (Box 111-113)
- Congressional hearing materials (Box 114-116)
- Speeches and writings (Box 117-119)
- Subject files (Box 120-125)
- Serial issues and technical reports (Box 126-129)
- Reactor safety study (Box 130-131)
- Handbooks and technical reports (Box 132-135)
- Chronological files, 1971-1973 (Box 136-138)
- Personal files (Box 136-138)
- Subject files (Box 139-147)
- Printed reports (Box 148-151)
- Subject files (Box 152-157)
- Congressional hearing materials (Box 158-161)
- Trip files, 1971 (Box 162-165)